watergrant.ie 2015-09-06

# Water Conservation Grant Application

This website is maintained by the Department of Social Protection. The Department of Social Protection fully respects your right to privacy, and will not collect any personal information about you on this website without your clear permission. Any personal information which you volunteer will be treated with the highest standards of security and confidentiality, strictly in accordance with the Data Protection Acts, 1988-2003 and applicable EU directives.

This statement relates to our privacy practices in connection with this website. Some technical terms used in this statement are explained at the end of this page.

Collection and use of personal information

This website does not collect any personal data, apart from information that you volunteer (for example, when applying for the Water Conservation Grant) and your IP address. Any information you provide in this way is used only for the purpose for which you provide it

Other technical Information we routinely collect

We may collect the following information from each user of this site:

  * Statistical information (IP address and hostname, web browser version, pages visited etc.).
  * The previous website address from which you reached us, including any search terms used.
  * Other information submitted in forms. 
  * The date and time you access our site.
  * Your language preference in accessing our site (English/Irish).

What we use the information for

Any personal information you provide will be used only for the purpose supplied, that is, in connection with the processing and administration of the Water Conservation Grant scheme.

The technical information may be used for statistical, investigatory and other administrative purposes. You should note that technical details, which we cannot associate with any identifiable individual, do not constitute 'personal data' for the purposes of the Data Protection Acts, 1988 – 2003.

Cookies

Cookies are small pieces of information, stored in simple text files, placed on your computer by a website. Some cookies can be read by the website on your subsequent visits. The information stored in a cookie may relate to your browsing habits on the webpage, or a unique identification number so that the website can 'remember' you on your return visit. Other cookies are deleted when you close your browser and only relate to the working of the website. Generally speaking, cookies do not contain personal information from which you can be identified, unless you have furnished such information to the website.

Cookies may be set in a number of places on this website. When you first visit this website, you will see a message informing you about cookies. If you click the 'I understand' button, a cookie will be set which records your preference.

Most browsers allow you to turn off cookies or to customise your settings for cookies. To find out how to do this, see the 'Help' menu on your browser. Please note that if you turn off cookies or change your settings, some features of this site may not work correctly.

Links

This website may contain links to other sites. The Department of Social Protection is not responsible for these sites or for the privacy statements of other websites. 

Notification of Change

The Department of Social Protection reserves the right to amend this statement at any future date and will post any substantive changes here.

## Glossary of technical terms used

Web Browser

A web browser is the piece of software you use to read web pages. Examples are Microsoft Internet Explorer, Chrome, Mozilla Firefox and Opera

IP Address

Your IP address identifies your computer (or your internet service provider’s computer) in internet protocol code (for example 123.456.78.90). Every computer connected to the web has a unique IP address, although the address may not be the same every time a connection is made.
